hello I'm your host David Barnard and my
guest today is Joseph Choy a former
e-commerce marketer who's now helping
app developers go viral on Tik Tok on
the podcast I talk with Joseph about
what's currently working for apps on Tik
Tok how to create viral content and why
you should try working with influencers
who don't have many followers hey Joseph
thanks so much for joining me on the
podcast today thanks for having me David
so we're going to be talking about Tik
Tok I think a lot of folks are going to
be excited to listen to this episode but
but before we get into some of the
techniques and things you're learning
and working on why Tik Tock and like
what got you into Tik Tok marketing I'll
give you a quick backstory when I was in
college I wanted to make money online I
was bored with my classes so I went on
YouTube I went listened to podcasts and
the the business that I found was Drop
Shipping it's like it's a fulfillment
model for e-commerce businesses where
you buy the product as soon as the
customer buys the product so you have
razor thin margins it's not a very good
business and the only differentiator you
have is copywriting and marketing and
ads so I got really good at ads and I
noticed that a lot of the e-commerce
marketers over the years have been
shifting into app development and it's
really interesting to me to see a lot of
the same e-commerce tactics that I sort
of learn Marketing in now being used in
the consumer Tech app space so in the
past few months I've just been meeting a
lot more Founders that are leveraging
Tik Tok and short form video to go viral
with their apps and I really think it's
a it's a great opportunity to get your
first you know thousand users 10,000 Mr
for subscription apps let's dive in then
and I I wanted to start with why Tik Tok
so you know there's so many ways to get
attention press and SEO and starting a
blog and like all these different things
but what's unique about t talk that
people are starting to find success and
that that it is maybe a good place to
experiment with zero to one when you
scroll on Tik Tok and you're scrolling
through the videos the videos that
you're seeing are not from people that
you follow I would approximate maybe 95
plus percent of the videos that you
scroll through are people that are from
creators that you've never seen before
so because of this there's just a ton of
watch time going to brand new accounts
brand new videos so as a Creator you can
make videos on Tik talk from zero
followers and get millions of views on
your first video I experienced this one
time myself I made a new account I made
a video with zero followers and I got
50,000 views on the first video and I
was just talking about like San Franc I
was living in San Francisco at the time
and I just started talking about SF
culture but people in the app space are
doing this too and I think that's what's
unique about Tik talk it's like you know
before you had to build up a following
on your Instagram or your Facebook or or
if you wanted to do ads you know you pay
for the content to put it in front of
people with Tik Tok you just have to
make good quality content it can go
viral from scratch yeah your your cost
of of marketing is is zero if you do it
yourself and then if you're paying a
Creator you can pay them a flat fee and
then get exponential return you
mentioned that you started in e-commerce
and it seems like e-commerce maybe was a
little earlier to the Tik Tok scene than
apps what do you think has changed or or
what do you think made it more
interesting for apps as of late so Tik
Tok shop launched in November of
2022 so it's November 2024 when we're
recording this it's only been two years
since Tik Tok shop launched Tik Tock
shop is basically an affiliate platform
for e-commerce products on Tik Tok so as
a brand owner you can upload your
e-commerce product to Tik Tok shop you
set an affiliate commission percentage
so some people do 15 to 20% and then
creators will automatically just sign up
for your to affiliate for your product
and start making videos and the payments
and everything is is handled through Tik
Tok so in the beginning this was a huge
goldw for Brands because you could just
upload your product and then pay
commission only to these Tik Tok
creators so over the past two years
there's been a big rush on the Creator
side for all these creators that are now
they see how much money you can make on
Tik Tok shop you know these 15%
commissions add up very quickly if you
go viral with a Tik Tok so now there's
this whole new class of creators that
it's really good at making video content
that's that not only gets views but is
high converting and actually you know
it's not just views as a vanity metric
like the it's actually driving millions
and millions of dollars of gmv just
through these Tik Tok shop creators so I
think the space as a whole of influencer
and Creator marketing has evolved and
people have invented new tactics for
storytelling and hooks and creative ctas
so Tik Tok shop has definitely fueled a
lot of the innovation in the marketing
side one of the companies I think is
really interesting in this space uh in
the e-commerce space is tabs chocolate
so they they went from zero to 10
million in Revenue in a year just on Tik
Tok shop and the founder of that Oliver
he put the tabs chocolate product on
hold and he switched to apps
so then he launched an app called study
buddy and it helps students with their
homework you know it's an AI app but he
used he was very transparent he built it
in public and he was saying hey I'm just
going to use all my knowledge of
e-commerce and just do the same
marketing but for this app because it's
higher margin it's higher exit multiples
higher retention so you know once he
started doing that then a bunch of apps
started catching on and you know doing
the same thing and I think it's yeah I
think this is the new wave I think like
naturally apps have always grown through
different ways but I think Tik Tok is I
think Tik Tok is the the new thing and
it's interesting I mean it's not that
apps are are suddenly going viral on Tik
Tok or that nobody's tried to make it
work before because like famously widget
Smith went viral on Tik Tok in 2020 so
four years ago it went viral went you
know shot to number one in the App Store
we've actually had David Smith the
developer of that on the podcast and we
we've talked to other apps that are
doing Tik Tok marketing but it seems
like maybe the why now kind of thing why
is it starting to blow up is that these
e-commerce folks have really kind of
pioneered the techniques that are now
actually going to start working better
for apps I think that's right yeah I
wanted to dive into your understanding
of the algorithm and you you kind of
already mentioned how the for you page
drives so much of this but I wanted to
dive a little deeper into that contrast
SEO you know so hard to get your page
ranked because almost any topics are
already so inundated as you mentioned
Instagram and Twitter and other typical
social media platforms Facebook having
to build up an audience before you can
like actually see scale it's just such a
different experience and so is there
anything else about the algorithm that
that you think makes it so effective for
going viral and as a marketing channel
there's a distinction between
influencers and what I like to call I
guess like SC cppy ugc creators in the
traditional sense of like what an
influencer is like I think influencers
became a thing around the Instagram era
maybe a little bit before but basically
they have like an influencer is really
if you think about it in a as an analogy
for creating a movie a movie production
which is what Tik Tok videos are
basically just short movies you have
like you have the director you have the
actor and then you have the audience you
know the distribution and an influencer
plays all three of those roles they're
the talent that shows up in the video
they're the creative director they
actually think of the video ideas and
then edit it and everything and then
they also have an audience the
pre-existing audience that they've built
trust with over the years through their
content but what Tik Tok allows you to
do as a brand owner or an app developer
is you can hire a Creator to play just
the role of the actor so if you know how
to do marketing you can
give them a script that you know will
perform well on the for you page so now
you're playing the role of of the
director and then now Tik Tok itself is
playing the role of the audience and the
distribution you don't need a
pre-existing audience and the creators
are willing to take this deal because a
lot of them are under monetized they're
just making videos a lot of them get
reached out to by e-commerce products
these big cpg companies that say hey
I'll give you a product for free and
then please make a video for us and
they're like that doesn't seem like a
great deal but fine I'll do it because
what else am I going to do I'm gonna
make the videos anyway may as well make
a little bit of money out of it so if
you're willing to put a little bit more
money into Creator marketing you know
the I think the foru page really enables
you to be scrappier with it that's a
great analogy that instead of having to
build an audience it's the content
itself that generates the audience
through Tik tok's algorithm are there
any specific things to the algorithm
that you're striving for to help it go
viral is it just about being engaging or
is it like getting more likes or other
inputs that you've seen to the algorithm
that set aside the content itself
because like we'll dive into what makes
great content but is there anything
specific to the
algorithm that helps it go viral other
than the content itself short answer is
no it is just the content itself what I
will say is I'm very skeptical of anyone
who claims to know what exactly the Tik
Tok Al algorithm is it's always changing
you know it's shifting like sometimes
people will say shares matter more
sometimes people will say likes matter
more watch time retention comments but
if you just think about it from a higher
level like think about if you're Tik Tok
if you own Tik Tok how would you want to
design the algorithm so like Tik Tok
makes its money from adver advertising
and from Tik Tok shop so if you want to
make the most money as Tik Tok you want
people to watch more videos for longer
just like any other social media
platform so if you want to get people to
watch more videos for longer then you
want to incentivize people to make
content that people watch the video to
its completion and then go on to the
next video and then watch that to
completion you know you want people to
like to enjoy watching the video and
have some sort of emotional reaction to
watching the video so when people say oh
it's just about making good content what
that really means is the hook has to be
good the retention has to be good and
like at the bottom line is you know
someone has to feel something when they
watch the video and I imagine the
algorithms probably fairly sophisticated
as well in that sometimes it's going to
feed you a 15-second video and sometimes
it's going to feed you a two-minute
video and so sometimes your two-minute
video will hit if it's engaging if we
think about it through like the base
Human Experience of Tik Tok it's like
driving that those little mini dopamine
rushes and so the algorithm is maybe
taking so many different things into
account like you said that no one thing
is always going to work because it's
going to depend on the on the context
like is the person is it 2 a.m. and
they're just like dopamine hit and they
need 15-second videos or is it or you
know are they more in a state where they
they can engage with a two-minute video
and so it's probably like so context
dependent what Tik Tok is going to feed
people that trying to guess at it is
like you said it's make people feel
something and that's going to be more
successful does having followers on Tik
Tok give you any kind of a leg up like
if you've got a million followers on Tik
Tok are you guaranteed to at least get
more of a shot or do you feel like even
with zero followers videos can go viral
and it doesn't matter as much as you
might guess yeah if you have a million
followers on Tik Tok that does give you
a legout for sure because you know I I
think I gave an estimate maybe 95% of
the videos you watch on the for you page
are brand new accounts that you've never
seen before but there also is a
following tab so if you scroll to the
left you can watch videos that from
people that you follow so you do reach
an audience when you post a video from
an account that has followers you do get
a boost for sure it's just that the vast
majority of the watch time comes from
the for you page so it's easier to go
viral than it was before so you have a
leg up and there specific strategies
that you've seen for apps be successful
in growing an audience or do you think
that the focus is more just content and
should an account like have a point of
view and and model some of the old style
influencer that this account is all
about you know like if I created one for
my weather app like should I strive to
create something people would actually
want to follow by sharing interesting
content in addition to any like pitch
kind of stuff or do you think it's more
important to just
really focus on on each video being as
potentially viral as possible yeah this
seems sort of like a business strategy
question like I feel like the long-term
goal is always to build a great brand
because that contributes to better SEO
and ASO and just general word of mouth
and brand love so I think it's always
great to build a brand I've seen that
Instagram reals is better for that
because there's actually a home feed
where it's just people that you follow
so it's a lot easier to reach your own
followers from an Instagram account so
yeah I think you know having a
legitimate brand Beyond just like going
viral every day it's always good yeah I
think that's always a good thing to have
yeah what kind of apps do you think this
works for you and I actually talked
about it directly in relation to my
weather app I forget the exact quote but
it was something along the lines of yeah
I just don't know like how viral you're
going to be able to go with a weather
app and like you know productivity apps
maybe widget Smith being an except
is it harder for productivity in those
sorts of apps and then what apps do you
think are the absolute best fit for this
kind of marketing yeah so Tik Tok is a
video platform so apps that have some
sort of visual element or highly visual
wow factor do very well on Tik Tok so
things like consumer social dating
personal finance health and wellness if
you have any of those apps that have
some sort of strong visual component
it's easier to make viral content about
those apps but you can get creative with
it if you look at the Tik Tok ad library
and you go to the top performing ads of
all time they're all utility apps
they're just you know things like phone
storage cleaners and AI spam calling
blockers and things like that one Niche
is that I've seen do really well is just
productivity apps so there's this app
because if you think about the types of
content that exists on Tik Tok there's a
lot of people that talk about things
from their personal experience like ADHD
or productivity motivation there's a lot
of content that exists in that Niche
already so partnering with creators in
that Niche or just copying the content
that already Works in that Niche it can
apply very well to things like
productivity apps and utility apps like
you're saying if you think about in
general like what type of marketing
works as a whole it's like health wealth
relationships right if it has to do with
either of those things so for example
productivity is somewhat about wealth
somewhat about health and you can attach
that type of Storytelling in your
marketing to the app weather is that
health wealth relationships I think
weather is a difficult one you were
saying you know looking at the top ads
these like phone cleaner and stuff like
that but are those going viral or is
that like those are successful as ads
because a lot of money is put behind
them because there there's those two
kind of things like a lot of what you've
been talking about on Twitter and you
know you have this community you're
building up of apps working to go find
viral and use Tik Tok as a marketing
channel but there's the like free
marketing go viral and then there's like
put money behind a piece of content and
that performing well so do you see those
kind of like productivity tools and you
know clean your storage and stuff are
those actually going viral or is it that
those just make so much money the
creators of those apps are able to put
so much money behind them on spend
they're primarily getting their users
through paid acquisition because they
can't go viral on Tik Tok that was my
point there I think the maybe I should
make a distinction there's productivity
apps that solve a deep pain point about
your day to-day motivation and building
habits it's a very emotional emotionally
tied product versus a productivity app
that cleans your phone storage it's a
somewhat emotional problem but it's not
it's not as deep it's more of a you see
an ad and the ad has a good creative and
you're just like oh that seems useful
let me download that and then there's a
pay wall and then you pay the pay wall
versus is a Tik Tok that says hey are
you struggling with motivation there's a
dream outcome that you can sell through
that type of content you could be 10
times more productive you start doing
habit tracking and then that sort of
like user experience and buying journey
is very different I think than strictly
utility app yeah so maybe that that's
where to draw the line and you kind of
said it earlier right it's like if you
have a productivity app that you can
make content that people really feel has
a a higher likelihood of going viral if
you have a productivity app like we've
been talking about that like clean your
storage like that people need that but
maybe those kind of ads are less likely
to go viral and get a lot of free boost
even if they can be very effective on
Tik Tok as a paid so thinking again
specifically about like my weather app
which you know we've talked about is is
probably going to be a challenge for me
to get going on Tik Tok if I try it's
that if I'm trying to go viral I need to
focus on that that feel side of things
and that's hard to do it's hard to
create that kind of feel content for
that kind of a utility versus like you
were saying a more kind of emotionally
driven utility or productivity app so
maybe that's a great way to draw those
distinctions I think it's possible also
to slightly change the products to
become more Tik Tock native so I've seen
people do this for example with health
tracking where you know if you have a
whoop or a Apple watch or Fitbit or
something
and that you're not satisfied with the
analytics there's these apps that are
doing better Biometrics and better
analysis which is not a fantastic pitch
for Tik Tok it's sort of like improve
your health by looking your analytics
like do end consumers really want to put
in the work to improve their health with
general like good health analytics not
really but what some of these apps are
doing is they choose one hook one viral
you know killer feature within their app
that will go viral on Tik Tok so for
example I've seen this new health graph
that tells you your anxiety levels
throughout the day and I don't know how
it does that it's maybe it's blood a
combination of blood pressure and
heartbeat or you know some other data
but it's a very novel thing like I've
never seen an app do that before and it
hits a pain Point that's very resonant
with a lot of people and the app might
do a whole bunch of things with your
health but on Tik Tok they emphasize
this one killer feature I've seen apps
you know create features just to go
viral on Tik Tok and then use that sort
of as a funnel to their main you know
the the whole ecosystem of features that
they have in their app yeah that makes a
lot of sense like and then that probably
somewhat informs your kind of go viral
strategy versus the kind of create a
great ad strategy is if you're
specifically trying to go viral you're
probably not you know listing all the
features or trying to it's like you you
specifically want to look for that hook
that's going to be unique that's gonna
make people feel that's gonna do all
those things that kind of leads me to
the next question which is and we've
already been talking about it but how do
you create great content on Tik Tok 15
seconds at a time 60 seconds at a time 2
minutes at a time I mean especially
tough because you're ultimately selling
something and we can get into the ctas
but like yeah what makes a good Tik Tok
creative as a founder or developer like
you can make content yourself so you can
get out your phone record your face and
just start talking about your app
there's another trending format right
now where it's just Tik Tok slideshows
so there's no it's like a carousel image
where it Scrolls through five five to 10
images with captions on the screen and
those are going really viral so there's
a lot of ways to make this content
yourself but in general how do you make
good content I think generally it has to
have you want it to go viral you want it
to views which we discussed earlier you
know it's it's about watch time
engagement something that could be
sharable and a good hetic for thinking
about that is if someone was watching
this video would they share it with a
friend so then if you think about like
if you said hey guys I just made this
app it helps you look at the weather and
the interface is is much you know better
than the normal weather app it's too
salesy like How likely would a an
average viewer watch that video and then
decide to send it to a friend what
emotional impact is that video having on
them that makes them think wow I need to
send this to my friends so how do you
create that emotion it's got to
basically it has to it has to be funny
it has to be controversial or it has to
have some sort of wow factor there's
probably some other emotions that you
could think of but if it has one of
those things High chance that people are
going to share it with their friends or
like the video or leave a comment but
then it also has to sell the products
too you have to to either show the
product or mention it you don't just
want views there's a tension there that
you want it to get good engagement but
then you also want to sell the product
the more you sell the product usually
the less sharable the video becomes it
is tricky but I can give one example so
there is this app that helps you to
record your lectures for college
students you audio record the lecture
and then it gives you an AI summary of
all the lecture notes based on the the
recording and and one of the really good
apps in this space it's called quizzard
Ai and they have a Tik Tok and Instagram
accounts and one of the video formats
that they do is they get a college
student to put a laptop in their lap
while they're sitting in the lecture
hall while the teacher is presenting
their lecture and then they have a
laptop screen open with the app open on
the screen and it's recording the
lecture and the student is like asleep
like you know like just sleeping in the
in the lecture and but the the camera
angle is it's a student behind them
filming over the shoulder and looking at
the student that's sleeping and
recording the lecture and the caption is
WTF the college isn't even real anymore
so it's relatable it's funny it's
controversial because kids are lazy
these days or whatever like college is a
scam and it directly shows product and
the value proposition of the product
that's one of the examples that kind of
hits really good engagement and also
selling the product really effectively
let's stick into a couple more examples
I know there's an ADHD habit tracking
app that's like doing really well on Tik
Tok what's their content like what's so
sharable about what they're doing this
might be a gen Z Trend but I think you
know gen Z cares a lot about mental
health sometimes gen Z over self
diagnoses on certain mental you know
illnesses D is definitely one of them
they kind of describe ADHD more as a
personality trait than an actual
diagnosis the trend is is out there and
people are talking about it so there's
all this existing
ADHD content where people are saying
does anyone else get that feeling when
you walk into a room and then you
completely forget why you were there oh
like ADHD things and you could do that
as a talking head video These creators
are speaking to the camera or they're
doing a skits where they show themselves
walking to the room then forgetting why
they're there procrastination on things
like their homework or their tasks so
the content is out there you just make a
slight change in the call to action of
those videos where you say hey anyone
else relat to this thing by the way I
use this app by the time they gets
halfway through the video they've
already given the algorithm the 50% 60
70% watch time and then you plug the app
you know at the end then people are like
well it's it's okay like I just got all
this related atable content and maybe
got a few tips for managing my ADHD plus
they just gave me this app that's really
useful it's almost like an infomercial
but just organically on Tik Tok you know
you got to give value and demonstrate
the value of the product by talking
about the pain points and then talking
about the solutions and including your
product as a solution for the topic that
you're talking about yeah that's really
cool and then another example uh RZ GPT
what are they doing content wise so Riz
GPT is a keyboard app that looks at your
dating app matches that you get on
Tinder or hinge or whatever and then it
suggests what to say to the person so
you know it's like it's sort of riding
this jenzy you know idea of Riz and
being charismatic over text and their
strategy is very interesting they have
dozens of Tik Tok accounts all posting
pretty similar content I don't know if
you've ever seen the split screen
content where you get like Subway
Surfers on the bottom and you get some
like Reddit story on the top or some
text message story on the top so Riz GPT
uses this format a lot in a lot of their
videos where they have Minecraft like
parkour video in the background or some
sort of gameplay video in the background
just to get people to keep watching but
then in the foregrounds they have
screenshots of Tinder conversations and
the Tinder conversations are basically
funny pickup lines that are generated by
the the app like by GPT another thing
they do is they do the screen recording
so they're live you know typing and then
there's a pause and they like oh no what
do I say and then they swipe over to the
Riz GPT app they input the the
screenshot and then it generates and
then they swipe back over to the dating
app and then input the line that they
just copied and pasted directly
demonstrates the product but of course
they put that segment at least 50% of
the way into the video so the the main
point of watching the content for most
viewers is to just watch this
entertaining conversation between two
people on a dating app but you know
certain percentage of people that watch
will relate to the content and say hey
actually I I use dating apps I sometimes
struggle with writing pickup lines so
I'm going to actually download this app
that they that they just shielded to me
people people know it's an ad you know
like they know it's an ad but if if it's
entertaining it's doesn't matter and are
those going viral are they you know
producing a lot that do go viral or is
that an example of ones they're having
to put a lot of money behind to get the
attention oh no these are these are very
viral and the virality there is is
probably the conversation right it's
like like weird Goofy and like they
probably try and pick like you want to
see what the person's going to respond
on Tinder to this crazy message or
whatever anything to do with dating I
mean there's a reason why everyone
gossips about relationships and dating
there's just a lot of good content that
can come out of it everyone relates in
some way to finding love and you know
talking to people that you're trying to
date so there's a lot of spiciness and
humor that can come out of that type of
content it seems like based on and is
fun to kind of dive into these specific
examples but I don't know that anyone
listening is going to be able to
replicate the exact format and the exact
success of these three that we've talked
about but it seems like so much of
getting good at Tik Tok and having
multiple videos go viral over time is
just watching what other people are
doing I'm learning are there any tips
for how to keep an eye on what's going
viral you know how people are
effectively doing this you should follow
me on
Twitter I post I post content about this
like the way that I do it is I just
scroll on Tik Tok I scroll on Tik Tok in
reals and I have swipe files so I have
multiple folders every time I watch a
video that seems like it is an ad not an
ad but it seems like it was paid for I
put it into one of my four swipe files
in the Tik Tok folders or the Instagram
reals folders and I categorize it into
what type of content it is so if it's
like a slideshow then I'll put it into
the slideshows folder if it's a talking
head content I'll put it into the
talking head folder if it's like a a
skit like the quizzard AI lecture hall
one I'll put it into the skit folder so
yeah I think just being a an active
consumer and like consuming from a
producer mindset is sort of how I've
always thought about marketing if you
want quick hacks for like just getting a
bunch of ideas for Content there's tools
out there I think if you just Google
like best performing Tik Tok you know
content for Brands I think there's a lot
of websites that kind of try to
aggregate some of that content it's kind
of funny because um you know when I'm on
Tik Tok or Instagram reals I'm a
middle-aged man Instagram knows that I
really like family humor so like you
know husband and wife humor but my point
in saying that is that if all you do is
scroll as a consumer you're going to
understand what goes viral with other
people like you and I wonder if like you
kind of have an advantage as a young
techie in New York City and like your
habits may be more aligned with those
kind of audiences where things are going
to go viral whereas like my like Dad
content on on Instagram I don't spend
much time on Tik Tok so I'm using
Instagram as example but it's like the
algorithms do kind of pigeon hole you
and so while like being a consumer helps
you probably want to find ways to kind
of break out Beyond where the the
algorithm has pigeon hold you so it
seems like those kind of websites and
other resources I've learned a lot
following you on Twitter to see what's
going viral in those age groups that
like I I don't see that kind of content
when I'm scrolling that's very true I
think the algorithm does pigeon hole you
if you're thinking about researching
content in a specific space there are
first party research tools that Tik Tok
does give you if you look up like Tik
Tok keyword research I think there's
tools that give you insights into
underutilized keywords for Tik Tok
search and then if you go on the Tik Tok
Creator Marketplace you can also find
creators that are putting themselves on
the marketplace to be hired for
sponsored content and you can filter by
Niche and if you look at their videos
and you can see like the the types of
branded content that they're making so
that's another good uh research tool you
mentioned it earlier but where do you go
to see what ads are performing really
well like storage cleaner apps
performing really well that's in their
ad product the Tik Tok ad Library so
just like the Facebook ads Library Tik
Tok has similar products where you can
just see all the top performing ads you
can even see the click-through rates and
the you know the watch time on the on
the ads so you can analyze the those
videos they they show you a lot of good
data yeah and I guess on on those though
it's probably you want to look at the
content that's going viral to get tips
for going viral and then you want to
look at the ad library for for like what
kind of content we create that we might
put money behind and like I imagine
there's enough overlap between those two
where you're going to get ideas for both
from watching either but I imagine you
need to kind of keep that context like
you're not going to go viral with some
of the techniques that these storage
cleaning apps are using in their ads
right definitely definitely that's
exactly right yeah the last part of
creating content that again we've
touched on but I want to dive deeper
into is how do you create effective call
to action pretty much anybody listening
to this podcast is not wanting to go
viral for viral sake they're wanting to
go viral to make money to drive people
to the App Store to download their app
or to go through a web flow to sign up
for a subscription how do you create
effective call to action in a Tik Tok
video yeah this is super important like
consumers in general not just on Tik Tok
but consumers are hyper aware of you
know things that feel like ads as a
general rule one interesting thing about
Tik Tok is a lot of these videos
promoting apps they don't mention Link
in BIO so that was a really popular
thing from Instagram era you know click
on the my Lin in BIO use this code to
check out that works well if you're an
influencer and you're pushing the
products to an audience that already has
trust with you but if you're watching a
random video in the for page it needs to
feel as authentic as possible because
you haven't built that audience trust
over time they're just watching a video
cold some examples of this are here's
the top five apps I use for XYZ paino
here's the top five apps I use for
tracking my progress in the gym that's
not a great hook you could probably put
more pain points and more dream
Solutions in that hook but you know you
name five different apps and then your
app is one of them it's a genuinely
useful video it's similar to you know
like Google SEO strategy where it's like
these are these articles are top five
credit cards and then obviously they're
all sponsored it's still genuinely
useful to the consumer because you're
giving them a variety of options and a
certain percentage of those people will
follow the call to action and go to the
the first one or the second one or
whichever one is your app another one is
there's with the slideshow content
there's this app called POV and the app
is a disposable camera app so you take
pictures and you can only view the
photos later sort of a nostalgic app
that brings back the the vibe of you
know actual disposable cameras but
they're going really viral on Tik Tok
with slideshow stories so they say you
know the first slide is so it's all
wedding based weirdly enough so they
they say here's five controversial rules
that we had at our wedding recently and
then there's this image of you know a
wedding and so that's a great hook it's
a very negative you know interesting
hook people are like oh what are the
controversial rules and then the rules
are controversial it's like oh no kids
at the wedding or no taking pictures and
then the no taking pictures kind of
hints at the last slide which is oh by
the way I had the guests use the POV app
from the App Store so instead of taking
pictures normally with cameras they have
to use this disposable camera app and it
created a better you know Vibe for
taking the pictures at the wedding so
than they have multiple accounts making
these slideshow videos and the app the
CTA there is you know I had the guests
use the POV app so it's a they directly
mention the app but it's part of a
storyline rather than saying hey go
download this thing yeah and it sounds
more organic too right because it's like
here's our five crazy rules at our
wedding one two three four and I used
the app to enforce rule number four or
whatever so yeah that's man that's
that's super slick one is this one's
really good for talking head content so
if you have Creator if you get a 100
creators to just start storytelling on
camera a good hook that a lot of people
are using in the e-commerce space and
the app space now is am I the only one
that saw that viral video from that XYZ
authority figure about this thing and
it's just like the viral video might
exist it might not but it's like it's
also ambiguous enough to where yeah of
course there's going to be lots of viral
videos about every topic but just saying
like oh am I the only one that saw the
viral video it just it's just a good
hook and eventually it'll get saturated
like everyone's going to say the same
hook and then people will start to catch
on that oh this is not organic but it is
a trend that I think is still quite
active right now yeah another another
CTA is I've seen this one in the ADHD
Niche going back to that but you just
start with a paino and then give helpful
tips so that you say oh if if you
struggle with ADHD here's this hack I
found or here's some tips about how to
deal with ADHD and then you give actual
tips and then you say oh also I use this
app it doesn't have to be at the end you
could use the the app as tip number
three out of five or you know but the
basis of the video is that here's a
bunch of here's these hacks that I a
life hack or ADHD hack actually if you
go on Tik Tok and you search hash ADHD
hack you'll get lots of examples of
these videos of people sharing their
ADHD hacks you can replicate some of
those copyrighting structures what's
interesting to me too is as we've been
talking through all of this and you said
it earlier is that some apps
specifically build features to go viral
and I wonder if that's actually a good
product strategy is that you know if
you're building features that people
care about that are interesting that
have some natural pain Point that's
going to bring people back into the app
like if you're building features that
don't have any kind of a hook that's
going to go viral on Tik Tok like are
you really like building something
valuable for folks that they're actually
going to use I mean that's what so many
apps I talk to really struggle with
retention because yes you created some
great solution for ADHD but it's a huge
pain to use or it doesn't have that like
emotional connection that's going to
bring you back to it or it doesn't have
that wow factor that's going to inspire
people to use it if this whole strategy
and finding things that are likely to go
viral on Tik Tok is actually a great way
to do feature Discovery product
Discovery and think of new apps to build
think of new features to build through
these framework you've essentially
shared over this whole podcast about
like what people are going to connect
with 100% I've even seen people build
apps in the completely opposite
direction where they do the marketing
first just for a weit list and they talk
about the app and the concept of it and
show figma screenshots and the app
doesn't even exist yet and they just get
people to sign up for a wait list and
that's instant product validation if you
get bunch of views on a Tik Tok that
talks about your app you get a bunch of
signups for for your weit list then you
can build the app after you Market it
there's this app called Breezy the the
founders in the community it's basically
a social note sharing app but it really
resonates with this certain demographic
of young genz people yeah she just makes
founder Le content talking about the app
itself showing figma screenshots some
beta screenshots and then it's a weit
list and she made a video that was 15
seconds long just talking about the app
and got I think 5,000 weightless signups
so yeah that was that was Breezy the
breey app I wonder if that's actually
even a good strategy too because as far
as hooks go that's another kind of hook
look like being an Insider being in the
no being early to something that's going
to blow up yeah I wonder if that's
actually a fun hook for folks to play
with is like as you're building a new
feature tease it in that way and like
hey you want to get on our beta or you
want to join the wait list for for when
this comes out versus building it first
and then creating the marketing that
could be a really cool strategy and then
you kind of like do that and like like
you're saying it's like that's that's
how you validate whether or not these
features are going to hit or not I've
built so many I I've launched 20 two
three apps over the last 16 years and
some were like hits and some were total
Duds there wasn't a ton of correlation
between you know the amount of time
spent or like I probably should have
found better ways to do product
validation ahead of time and so so for
you know side project apps today for big
apps that are looking for new features
that's a really cool idea for doing some
product validation ahead see if it goes
viral on Tik Tok and if it doesn't maybe
it's not the feature to build next I
just want to give one more thing
relating to this this is a infinitely
repeatable tactic that just it happens
year year over year it's just Spotify
wrapped if you just remake Spotify
wrapped but for XYZ Niche that concept
goes viral every single year reliably
like the the most recent one is the
verse app it's a consumer social app and
they just did a design they generated an
AI image a bedroom based on the the
style of the music that you listen to
and then they Ed that as a hook for the
for the consumer social app and it went
super super viral I think they hit
number one in the app store for a few
days wow so the last thing I wanted to
talk about was working with influencers
so I'm a good example that I don't think
me getting on Tik Tok is going to settle
out you middle-aged man you know talking
about abs like there'll be a lot of
folks like you who will in your framing
be the actor the director and kind of do
everything and I think for people who
can pull that off that's going to be a
ton of fun but for a lot of folks like
they're not going to be able to do this
themselves and so finding creators to
work with is going to be a huge part of
making this successful so yeah what are
your top tips for finding and working
with creators to help Implement what
we've been talking about I think
influencer marketing
traditional influencer marketing is very
expensive if you reach out to some of
these creators on who have you know more
than 100,000 followers a lot of them
will hit you back with their Media Kit
and it's all sometimes they even have an
agent a talent agent that inflates the
prices even more charge you thousands of
dollars for a single video you want to
avoid those people they can be good to
work with if it's a really really strong
audience fit but if you want to get a
lot more Roi in a scrappier way I like
going after a very low follower count
creators so finding people that have
less than 50,000 followers who've maybe
hit one or two viral videos in their
time on Tik Tok but maybe don't go
consistently viral because if they're
going consistently viral they're going
to be more expensive but if they hit one
or two viral videos they know the
feeling of what it takes to go viral
like they probably thought about oh why
did that video go so viral oh like it's
the way that I said these words in these
ways the way that I did the hook so they
sort of Know What It Takes and then
lastly is just like human touch just
like look at how they present themselves
are they charismatic on camera if
they're charismatic on camera they have
low follower count they know how to make
viral videos but are not super monetized
with sponsor videos yet that's the
perfect person that you want to reach
out to they're probably not making that
much money from Brand deals so you can
pay them cash and they'll gladly they'll
probably gladly take it'll take a little
bit more training you know teaching them
about the app and telling them how to
structure the the video script and
things like that but yeah I think
finding low follower count but
charismatic creators is is the way to go
and then how would you suggest
structuring payment expectations in
those kind of low fer account they're
probably aspiring creators not you know
they don't have an agent do you write a
contract like what do you offer the
creators and and how do you structure
the deal to make it work yeah so a lot
of these creators are used to getting
reached out by these big cpg you know
e-commerce companies they just do gift
gifted campaigns so they just get a prod
a free product in exchange for video so
in your Outreach message whether it's an
email or a DM if you just say I want to
pay you like explicitly say I want to
pay you for a video in cash you don't
have to say how much you know you can
figure out negotiating the rates later
but say explicitly I want to pay you for
video my app is you know it does this I
think your audience would be a great fit
I really like your content and then
typically how you structure that deal is
you know as I was saying before the CTA
in these videos is not always Link in
BIO so there's not going to be
attribution for a lot of these videos so
what you actually do is you give them
bonuses for views so if they get a bunch
of views then you can pay them per view
and then in addition you can give them a
base rate for making videos another
thing is since they're such a low
follower account Creator and you know
you want them to go viral on the foru
page you can have them make a brand new
account so you can have them make a new
Tik Tok account and name it something
else that's you know a little bit more
branded towards your app have them post
on it every day so a lot of these deal
structures are you can have them post
one Tik Tock per day for a month so 30
videos a month and the cost on that is
anywhere from I've seen $500 all the way
up to
$3,000 so at $3,000 that would be $100
per video which is still like fairly
cheap how much to pay just basically
just depends on their level of
experience and how much Roi you expect
to get out of it I have a friend member
of the community who's paid a one
Creator 3,000 a month and they got their
first 20K Mr from just one Creator just
posting every day so the retainer you
get what you pay for you know if you pay
for a really good cre Creator it'll pay
dividends but then the incentivization
is also good too so a typical rate that
I've seen for that is $1,000 per million
views or you can cut it where it's $500
per 500,000 views which works out to be
$1 CPM which is very very cheap and you
can play around with the rates depending
on what the what the Creator wants the
thing about paying a CPM though is it it
has to actually deliver and so if they
create something that like goes insanely
viral but doesn't actually send people
to the app or sends people to the app
that aren't going to be payers I could
see easily getting pretty upside down
have you seen any examples of that or
have you experienced that yourself like
you do this on a CPM basis and that it
goes crazy viral gets five million views
now you're on the hook for five grand
but then the CTA wasn't very strong and
like you don't make much money on it
yeah totally I mean that that's why like
the the Creator brief is like very very
important you know you should agree
beforehand on all the things that are
required from every single video so if
you know you know generally what your
strategy is and what you think will be
high converting videos then you should
give those guidelines and say you have
to have the CTA in this way so
definitely important to make sure that
the videos are viral and high-converting
yeah earlier you mentioned that in
eCommerce part of what really blew up
was the affiliate model with Tik Tok
shops do you think there's potential for
that on Tik Tok with apps doing
Affiliates like I've actually talked to
and probably have on the podcast at some
point the founder of go market me and
what they're trying to do is build a
platform for Affiliates like in what
cases do you think it would work what do
you think are the the potential there of
actually just doing a REV share where
essentially infinite upside like if
somebody created that video and instead
of getting paid $5,000 to get 5 million
views if that 5 million views actually
generated $100,000 and you're giving a
50% of you know first conversion or
whatever and they can make 50k I mean
seems like for a lot of creators this
opportunity to make infinite money would
be more interesting but it's tough so
yeah what are your thoughts on affiliate
on Tik Tok I think it's it's great it's
always the gold standard of marketing
for as the brand owner like obviously it
would be great to have zero risk up
front and just have people do free
marketing for you and only pay if they
generate revenue for you the problem is
yeah like Tik Tok is consumers are very
Savvy they don't really like clicking
links in BIO they want to feel like you
know this video is just telling them
about an app they go search on the App
Store themselves they download it I
think it can work for influencer
marketing if you have an influencer who
has an established audience and they're
getting a cut of the Lincoln bio clicks
I think that has always been and will
will always be a good way to partner
with with creators if it's like
traditional influencer marketing they
have an audience they have a lot of
trust but typically with those deals
there's there's always a base rate in
addition I think there's a talent
constraint or there's a supply
constraint of good creater talent I
think creators actually have like the
big creators like with audiences they
have a lot more power than the brands
they're getting reached out to by tons
of Brands all the time competing for
their attention and doing deals so
that's why I sort of advocate for the
you know the scrappy Creator marketing
non-traditional influencer marketing
because in that equation I think the
supply demand is is reversed I think
there's a lot more creators that are
underpaid that Brands can start paying
so Tik Tock shop for apps can definitely
exist um within like a certain context
of influencer marketing I've actually
been playing with um offer codes
recently it's something again I'll
probably do a whole podcast on or or uh
write something up about the experiments
I've been doing but what's interesting
about offer codes is that you get 100%
attribution on those do you think that
could be incorporated into a call to
action of like use Code Black Friday
yeah like I'm probably going to do a
Black Friday promotion so it was top of
mine but use code whatever to get 20%
off or do think like on Tik Tok that
kind of thing just wouldn't work like
use code whatever even if it's
incentivized like getting a discount do
you think that's too overt of a call to
action for it to actually work on Tik
Tok I think if you got creative with it
it could definitely work it just can't
be in the same way that you would sell
the promo code through an influencer
like I think it'll always work with
influencer marketing like we were saying
before but for the scrappy Creator
marketing if a random Creator on the for
you page with zero trust with the
audience says use promo code this at
checkout for the discount it feels like
an ad it's not going to go viral but
imagine if you if you had the Creator
say guys did you see that code like I
just used it have you seen this hack
that you can use to like get this thing
for 50% off maybe that could I don't
know how legal that is but I mean
there's there's probably other ways you
know there's there's always creative
ways that you can incorporate codes so I
could see some potential with that well
Joseph it's been fascinating I've I've
learned a ton I think this is going to
be really interesting to folks
especially just this kind of new trend
that it you know we've talked about Tik
Tok for years but it does seem like
people are figuring it out in a way
that's different than it has been in the
years past and I knew you actually have
a community of Founders who were all
working on this and trying to correct I
actually joined a few weeks ago and
that's part of how we met anything else
you wanted to share about the community
or anything else you're working on
definitely I appreciate having you the
community it's been great seeing you
around yeah the community is a
membership Community for Consumer app
Founders about half of them are Venture
backed half of them are bootstrapped
everyone has some form of traction
whether it's users or revenue or funding
some of the founders include the
founders of calm the meditation app womo
AI Bloom Investing For Teens autopilot
copy trading the founder of yikyak lots
of people of different backgrounds are
finding value from the community whether
it's Venture backed and you're trying to
learn these Scrappy marketing strategies
or you're bootstrapped and you're just
learning to you want to you know find
the the current edge of Tik Tok organic
and other user acquisition we're a
pretty pretty small community just
trying to keep it tight knit just
sharing the the latest tactics the
community is been great you Discord so
it's it tends to be extra chatty and I
don't have you know a ton of time to be
following along with the chat but I love
how you do the weekly summaries so every
week you kind of take the best insight
cuz it's your community and you do have
the time to be following and chatting
with folks and stuff so the weekly
summaries are are like super high signal
and kind of the best of conversation and
tactics and what's working what's not
and then I mean really this whole
podcast was kind of that high level
overview of all the things you're
learning in the community from other
Founders and things you've you've
learned yourself that you're sharing
with Founders in the community so thanks
for sharing so much today and then we
are for those listening in early
December I believe it's December 4th
we're going to be doing a webinar where
we actually dig into into some of the
specific videos that are going viral
some of the tactics we're going to I
don't know all the things we're going to
cover but we're going to have some fun
Joseph and I on this webinar and if
you're listening after the webinar it'll
be posted to YouTube so as a companion
to this episode that webinar is going to
be fantastic to like dive in more
directly to show what's working and
what's not working and actually see the
video see the acting see the call to
action so yeah really looking forward to
talking to you again so soon and we'll
have a link to sign up for the webinar
and then once the webinar has happened
we'll link to the YouTube in the show
notes we'll also link to the community
and your Twitter so yeah if you if
you've enjoyed this episode want to
learn more about Tik Tok go to the show
notes and sign up for the webinar or
view the YouTube video Joseph thanks so
much for joining me this is a ton of fun
thanks so much for having me this been
fun thanks so much for listening if you
have a minute please leave a review in
your favorite podcast player you can
also stop by chat. sub club.com to join
our private community
[Music]